Pengfan Zhang

Summary

Detail-oriented rising junior at New York University, experienced in web design and front-end development, active teamplayer, confident in software and programming skills, with passion in tech field. Actively looking for 2021 summer software engineer internship

• Fast Learner

Self-learned the new frameworks NuxtJs, Vuetify, and applied to web development to improve coding efficiency, receiving praised from the team leader

• Communication

Effectively communicate and presented projects to teammates

Programming Languages

Java (3 yrs), HTML (1 yr), CSS (1 yr), JavaScript (1 yr), C (1 yr)

Software Skills

GitHub, MS Office, MS Visual Studio Code

Languages

Mandarin (fluent), English (fluent)

New York, NY 10001 | 9172397253 | pz723@nyu.edu | LinkedIn | GitHub

Education

New York University

New York, NY Expected May 2023

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Computer Science

Cumulative GPA: 3.89/4.00 Honor: Dean's List (2019-2020)

Relevant Courses: Intro to Web Design, Data Structure, Computer System Organization, Basic Algorithm

Internship Experience

US Cabinet Depot

Kennesaw, Georgia

Software Engineer

Jun. 2021 – Aug. 2021

- Worked in a group of 4 to develop a new e-commerce and marketing website, updated the latest progress to team leader individually per week
- Applied framework Nuxt.js and Vuetify to design responsive layout of marketing page and customer check out page
- Separated front-end codes and content data from marketing pages to improve efficiency of informational page-updating

Project Experience

Carbonology, TreeHacks 2021

Feb. 2021

- Brainstormed themes of a Web APP with 3 teammates, researched 2 APIs and created the APP demo in 48 hours
- Used ReactJs to enable numerical data and links uploads, processed uploads by Carbon Interface API and Clarifai API
- Designed user interface for computers and mobile devices using Bootstrap and CSS, received and displayed the calculated result

College Info. Station Jan. 2021

- Developed website for searching general information of universities and colleges in the U.S.
- Utilized ReactJs to support retrieved data through College Scorecard API, visualized the numerical data by React Minimal Pie Chart Package
- Designed user interface by Bootstrap, and displayed results with animation and illustrations
- Published the website, browsed by 172 users according to Google Analytics

MLA Citation Format Generator

Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Individually developed a website to edit academic citations in MLA format, designed user interface by CSS
- Utilized HTML, JavaScript to upload information or ISBN number, processed ISBN input by Google Book API, and generated citations
- Published the website, used by 122 users base on Google Analytics

MineSweeper Game

Nov. 2019

- Utilized Java to create a mine sweeper game, implemented functions of left clicking and right clicking with responses
- Applied graphical library to process the interface of unopened and opened cells, flags, and ending scene
- Shared the demo to 20+ classmates, scored an A as final result

Volunteer

Intl. Dept., the Affiliated High School of SCNU

Guangzhou, China

Group Leader

Dec. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Led a group of 15 to purchase ingredients and prepare the food beforehand
- Assigned members into 4 groups to sell homemade Spanish foods and drinks on the International Day, raised \$100+ and donated to the Guangzhou Social Welfare Institute